When you only have 24 hours in the day to
make sure you complete everything that you need to get done,
how do you still make sure you handle all
of your responsibilities, but still make time for yourself,
friends, and family? This is where balance comes in.
But what does balance mean, and what does a
balanced life even look like? Balance to me is the
act of making time for the things you have to do,
as well as time for the things you want to
do as well. But to be completely honest, and before we
get into the bulk of this video, there's something that
I want to talk about, and that is that in
everyone's life, you are going to go
through periods of life of imbalance. Especially, let's
say you're an entrepreneur, for example. If you're working
on a project that is going to have the
potential to change your life and the lives
of others, you're going to be working 16-hour days
sometimes, and those are going to be, those are
not very balanced days. You're not going to be
talking to your friends and family during those
times, or maybe you're a parent with a
newborn. You're not making your schedule. You're working
off the schedule of that baby right there,
right? And that's just something to give
you perspective that in everyone's life, it's okay
to have certain pieces of imbalance. But in today's
video, we're going to be talking about the other
80-85% of your life where, hey, you can
actually implement things into your life to have balance.
So why is balance important? And the biggest
reason, and at number one, we have it improves
your mental health. So why is balance important? And the biggest
reason, and at number one, we have it improves your mental health.
Your mental health should be your number one priority at all times, especially when it comes to just
yourself, loving yourself, your relationships, and how others treat you, and just work and life in general, right?
And so how do you know if your work-life balance is necessarily unhealthy? And
one of the best things that I could recommend is pause and ask yourself,
what's actually stressing me out? What am I prioritizing right now? And actually just
take a moment to reflect on what's going on in your life, because I oftentimes
I feel like as people and humans is when we get so busy and caught up within the swing of things and just the day-to-day
of life, we never actually take a moment to actually reflect and see what we're actually prioritizing and what we're actually focusing on right now.
But just pausing and taking a moment to think about the way you're living and the way you're working, whether if it's working for you or not, and having
that moment in that discussion with yourself of, hey, is this the direction I want to keep taking things or do I want to take things a new route?
And number two of why balance is important is
because it prevents burnout.
And if you don't know what burnout is, to put it simply, burnout is where
you don't have the strength nor desire to continue working on what you're working on.
And if you have never burned out on a project or in your
career field, I hope you never do because it truly is a terrible feeling.
You genuinely feel detached, unimaginative, uncreative.
You just, you have no desire to work at all.
And that is one of the biggest problems.
And one of the biggest problems that I see
is that you're not able to work at all.
And that is one of the biggest problems.
The things that stem from a lack of balance.
The third and final point of why balance is important
is because it improves your motivation when you're at work.
When you're in a better mental state and
you are more efficient when you're at the workplace,
you get more time on your hands to spend time on doing things that you want to
do and it gives you more freedom to work on the things that you want to work on.
And when you're able to go home and just work
on things and do the things that you want to do,
whether that be spending time with your kids,
playing video games or working on a passion project,
that's what balance allows you to do is just segment your
life successfully in the way that you want it to be.
All right. All right.
Enough with why balance is important.
How do I actually become balanced?
So the number one thing that's been most helpful
for me is simply put, just scheduling out my day.
So this is going to be
different for everybody because I don't know.
Maybe you're a doctor.
Maybe you are a construction worker.
Everyone that's watching this
video has a different perspective.
Everyone has a different career path.
For me personally, I'm an entrepreneur, so I have a
little bit more freedom in how I make my schedule.
Right. So here's how I have made mine.
And this is really I follow a time blocking method.
And when I was growing up, I would always stay
up very late and then also get up very late.
Or if I get up early, I would just be exhausted and not
really focused because I got like two, two to three hours of sleep.
Right. But now what I've come
to notice is that in the morning,
I am actually the most balanced person in the world.
I am the most productive and the most focused, really,
just because there's the least amount of distractions in the morning.
So that's where I get in all my deep work, all
the tasks that needs the most attention and focus for me.
But then so I'll time block my workday very specifically of like, hey, I have
this task for 45 minutes, this task for an hour, this task for 30, 30 minutes.
And that has been really helpful for me because I've noticed that if you
give yourself one hour to do a task, you'll get it done in no time.
And that's what I've been doing
for the past couple of weeks.
I've been doing it for a long time.
But if you give yourself two hours to
do a task, it might take 30 minutes.
That means you're going to work for 30
minutes and then bullshit for the other hour, 30.
Right. So time blocking during the
workday has been very effective for me.
But when it comes after that, this is where
you can be as flexible or strict as you like.
I typically pretty loose on this.
But like, hey, you want to put like get a car car
wash for an hour, lunch hour and then spend time with kids.
Make sure you call mom.
If you want to put all that in your schedule.
Yeah.
You can.
But I typically just make sure I schedule out
my workday and then after that, I'm pretty flexible.
I just let the day take me.
Number two, we have having a clean desk and a good work environment, having everything you need
around you so that we don't have to get up frequently and lose focus is incredibly important.
Because what I've noticed, if I can just grab something that I need and it's on my desk
and I have it readily available to me, then I can just stay in the zone way longer.
And just get my work done, done,
get my work done way more efficiently.
So having a clean desk and a good work environment is really important to just making sure
that, hey, I'm staying efficient and I can just get my tasks done as soon as possible.
And another thing that I want to talk about is and this is number three, is making sure that you
have hobbies outside of work or just passions outside of work that allow you to have fun and just feel refreshed.
That way, when you go back to work, you don't.
It's not like you didn't do anything.
You know, like actually doing stuff outside of work rather than just like, I
mean, maybe if you want to just go on social media all night, that's it.
That's your thing.
Like, go for it, I guess.
But for me, it's like, hey, if I can go to the gym, do something physically active, if I can go to dinner with my friends or if
I can go bowling or just do some sort of activity that allows me to just escape and just do something that I genuinely love and enjoy to do.
でね
When I go back to work that
next morning, it's refreshing because it's almost like,
hey, I can just work on this and then
I have something else that, hey, I can look forward
to it or I have that aspect
of my life that I also enjoy, right?
So making sure you have a balance of like, hey,
this is my work time and this is my time
to where I can just do whatever I want
to do, whether that's read in a hammock or go
play video games for five hours.
It doesn't matter.
Just making sure you have activities outside
of work that you genuinely enjoy to do.
The final point is spending time
with family and really close friends.
And if you can make time for this every
single week and maybe if you don't live close to
them, making some time to just call them out
of the day and just connect with them because
these are the people that when you go
through your darkest moments, they're going to be
the ones that support you.
And when you have your wins, they're also
going to be those people first in line to
support you, right?
So making sure you spend people who give
you actual just genuine, nice intentions and love
and energy is so important.
And it's honestly just so refreshing to hang
out with those people because it's just pure
love, right?
But that's going to be it for me.
That's actually wrapping up this video.
Hopefully you guys enjoyed.
If you guys did, please
leave us a like and subscribe.
We really appreciate it.
Lots of awesome videos coming to this channel soon.
I'll catch you guys in the next one.